I-DA CHIANG

E-mail: idchiang@asiaa.sinica.edu.tw | LinkedIn: idchiang

RESEARCH INTERESTS

Dust Life Cycle & Interstellar Medium

I am interested in the evolution of dust in the interstellar medium. One of my project is measuring the spatially resolved dust-to-metals ratio in the nearby galaxies, and interpreting the results with dust chemical evolution models, simulations and auxiliary data.

HI 21 cm Line & Radio Astronomy

The distribution of neutral gas is a key element in dust-to-metals ratio studies. The HI 21 cm line traces neutral hydrogen atoms in the ISM. I reduced new HI 21cm line data of \sim 30 galaxies observed by VLA with CASA. These new data allows us to construct a new dust-to-metals ratio survey in the nearby galaxies.

EXPERIENCE

Institute of Astronomy and Astrophysics, Academia Sinica

Sep. 2021 - Current

Postdoc Fellow

University of California San Diego

Sep. 2014 - Jun. 2021

Graduate Research Assistant

- Built a python-based toolkit for dust SED fitting and multi-wavelength data analysis.
- Analyzed the dust-to-gas and dust-to-metal ratios in the spiral galaxy M101.
- Analyzed the dust-to-metal ratio and CO-to- H_2 conversion factor in detail in ~ 50 nearby galaxies
- Examined the empirical radiation distribution law and the turbulent power spectrum in the local group galaxies with the dust SED fitting tools.
- Reduced H_I 21cm line data of ~30 galaxies observed by VLA with the Common Astronomy Software Applications package (CASA).

University of California San Diego

Sep. 2014 - Jun. 2016

Teaching Assistant (TA) and Lab TA Coordinator

- Familiarized new teaching assistants with lab setups and teaching skills.
- Led discussion sessions, which helped ~ 40 students each week.
- Led introductory level physics lab, with 24 students per session.
- Improved course materials from feedback from teaching assistants and students.

National Taiwan University

Sep. 2012 - Jun. 2014

Graduate Research Assistant

- Improved the photo-degradation reactor for wastewater treatment with plasmonic nano-particles.
- Built the protocol for maintaining/using the sputter machine and clean room.

Taiwan (R.O.C.) Armed Forces

Aug. 2011 - Jul. 2012

Second Lieutenant (Company second-in-command)

EDUCATION

University of California San Diego

Sep. 2014 - Jun. 2021

Ph.D. (Physics and Astronomy)

Thesis: "Observations of Spatially Resolved Dust Evolution in Nearby Galaxies"

Adviser: Prof. Karin M. Sandstrom

National Taiwan University

Aug. 2012 - Jul. 2014

M.S. (Physics)

Thesis: "Plasmonic Enhanced Optical Disk Reactor for Wastewater Treatment"

Adviser: Prof. Din Ping Tsai

National Taiwan University

Sep. 2007 - Jun. 2011

B.S. (Physics)

REFEREED PUBLICATIONS AS FIRST OR SECOND AUTHOR

- 4) **I-D. Chiang**, K.M. Sandstrom, J. Chastenet, E. Koch, K. Kreckel, A.K. Leroy, A. Schruba, D. Utomo, T. Williams, "Resolving the Dust-to-Metals Ratio and CO-to-H₂ Conversion Factor in the Nearby Universe", 2021, ApJ, 907, 29.
- 3) E.W. Koch, **I-D. Chiang**, D. Utomo, J. Chastenet, A.K. Leroy, E.W. Rosolowsky, K.M. Sandstrom, "Spatial power spectra of dust across the Local Group: No constraint on disc scale height", 2020, MNRAS, 492, 2663.
- 2) D. Utomo, I-D. Chiang, A.K. Leroy, K.M. Sandstrom, J. Chastenet, "The Resolved Distributions of Dust Mass and Temperature in Local Group Galaxies", 2019, ApJ, 874, 141.
- 1) **I-D. Chiang**, K.M. Sandstrom, J. Chastenet, L.C. Johnson, A.K. Leroy, D. Utomo, "The Spatially Resolved Dust-to-metals Ratio in M101", 2018, ApJ, 865, 117.

A full publication list at ADS Public Library is available <u>here</u>.

RESEARCH PRESENTATIONS

Contributed talk, "Dust, gas and metals: Resolving the Dust Life Cycle in the Nearby University The AAS 235th Meeting, Honolulu, USA	erse", 2020
Special seminar, "Dust-to-Metals Relation in Nearby Galaxies", ASIAA, Taipei, Taiwan	2019
Poster, ASROC2019, Taichung, Taiwan	2019
Contributed talk, "The Variation of the Dust-to-Metals Ratio in Resolved Nearby Galaxies", the Universe, Tucson, USA	Dusting 2019
Lunch talk, University of California, San Diego, USA	2019
Tea time talk, University of California, San Diego, USA	2018
Poster, CPHDUST, Copenhagen, Denmark	2018
Poster, ASROC2018, Kinmen, Taiwan	2018
Lunch talk, University of California, San Diego, USA	2018

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Lab TA Coordinator, PHYS 1-ABC Lab – University of California, San Diego	2015 - 2016
Teaching Assistant, PHYS 1-A Lab – University of California, San Diego	2014 - 2015

OUTREACH EXPERIENCE

Python workshop for physics undergrads – presenter	2019
STEM in Your Backyard: City Heights – presenter	2018
Tech Trek: University of California, San Diego – presenter	2017
Physics GRE bootcamp at UCSD – teaching assistant	2016
AWARDS	
Dean's Award, College of Science, National Taiwan University	2014
Dean's Award, College of Science, National Taiwan University	2011
Presidential Award, National Taiwan University	2011